那人不是我杀的  迈克尔
I didn't kill that man. Michael
但是证据确凿
The evidence says you did.
我是被陷害的
I was set up.
把枪放下
Put down your weapon.
我有义务判你入狱
I find it incumbent you see the inside of a prison cell.
我想找个人  他叫林肯·布伦斯
I'm looking for someone,his name's Lincoln Burrows.
杀死副总统哥哥的那个?
He killed the vice president's brother.
你为什么这么急着要见布伦斯?
Why you wanna see Burrows?
因为他是我哥哥
He's my brother.
我要把你带出去
I'm getting you out.
不可能
That's impossible.
除非这个监狱是你设计的
Not if you designed the place.
你看过蓝图了?
You've seen the blueprints.
不止如此
Better than that.
我把他们都纹在身上了
I've got 'em on me.
你得找出是谁要至他于死地
You find out who's trying to bury him.
没人要他死
Nobody is.
证据确凿
The evidence was cooked.
又来了个好管闲事的律师
A lawyer's poking around.
任何威胁到咱们的人都要除掉
Anyone that's a threat is expendable.
斯科菲尔德
Scofield
给你找来个新朋友 海威尔 过来
Found you a new cellie.Haywire,get in here.
有人找到了菲波纳奇
Someone found Fibonacci.
是谁?
Who was this someone?
菲波纳奇到底在哪儿?
Where is Fibonacci?
我要告诉你  那才死定了
I give you that information,I'm a dead man.
给我起来
On your feet.
才几点啊?
What time is it?
快起来
Get up.
发生什么事了?
What's going on?
贝利克
Bellick.
贝利克 不要
Bellick. No!
贝利克 你要把我带哪儿去?
Bellick! Where are you taking...
贝利克 贝利克 不要啊
Bellick,Bellick, No! Bellick!
不 贝利克 不要
No! Bellick,no!
贝利克  不 还有一个月呢
Bellick,no! I got a month.
求你了 不要 贝利克
Please,no,Bellick!
贝利克 不要
Bellick,no.
贝利克  求你了
Bellick,please,no!
不 不 还有一个月呢
No,I got a month
求你了
Please!
不 贝利克
No,Bellick...
安息吧  林肯
Make your peace,Lincoln.
开始吧
Let's get on with it.
打开40号
Open 40.
关闭40号
Close 40.
海威尔  你想过逃出去么?
Haywire,you ever thought of breaking out?
我出去后又能做什么呢?
What the hell would I do out there?
只要不在这儿
Not be here.
精神病院?
Halfway houses.
看医生  吃药  定期接受检查?
Psych visits.Meds. Checking in with the PO.
尿检  如此反复...
Urine tests. Keeping a job.
我才不要呢
No.
为什么这么问?
Why'd you ask?
昨天有人在院子里问我这个 我不知道怎么回答
This guy was talking about it in the yard.I didn't know what to say.
告诉贝利克长官
Tell Officer Bellick.
他会帮你的  如果...
He'll make life easier for you if...
如果什么?
If what?
你的纹身
Your tattoos.
纹身怎么了?
What about them?
刻的是什么?
What are they of?
看起来像是某个...
Like,some kind of...
只是纹身罢了
They're just tattoos.
该吃药了  海威尔
Candy time,Haywire.
他们认为我患有严重的精神分裂症
They think I have schizo-affective disorder with bipolar tendencies.
你觉得有吗?
Think you got it?
无所谓了
Whatever.
服下药丸  蠢医生就会走了
I take the pills to keep the quacks off my back.
再见
Bye,now.
闪开
Get out to the way.
或许他们给你这东西是有原因的
You know,maybe they give you those things for a reason.
没错
Yeah.
为了把我变成白痴
To keep me dull.
用一双无形的手铐锁住我
To keep me in their invisible freaking handcuffs.
不过说真的  那纹身真不错
Seriously. Those tattoos,they're beautiful.
介意我完整的看看么?
You mind if I,you know,look at the whole thing?
事实上  我介意
I do,actually.
为什么?
Why?
你 站开
Yo. Stand clear.
需要理由么?
Does there need to be a reason?
苏克雷
Sucre.
我不能和你说话  伙计
I'm not even talking to you,man.
有什么不对头么?
What's the problem?
没有我解决不了的
Nothing I can't handle.
我知道有事
Well,I knew there was a problem.
我在院子那头就看出事情有些不对了
I could tell by looking at you from across the yard.
伙计们  我就说有事情不对吧?
Guys,didn't I say there was a problem?
到底是怎么回事?
So what's the problem?
你自己看
You're looking at it.
什么? 海威尔?
What,Haywire?
没错  我的新狱友
Yup. He's my new cell mate.
这就有问题了
That's a problem.
他从不睡觉
He doesn't sleep.
那你都什么时候挖?
So when do you dig?
我没法挖
I don't.
嘿  咱俩现在可是在一条船上
Hey,you and I are in bed now.
你答应过我
You made me a promise.
你说过咱们会逃出去的
You said that we were gonna get out of here.
要是食言  我就宰了你
You renege now,and I'm gonna cut you.
你好自为之吧
You better take care of your business.
要不然我就给你好看
Or I will take care of you.
祝你今天过得愉快
Have a nice day.
真的能弄好么?
It's really coming together,isn't it?
是的
Yup.
能按时完工?
You think it'll be done in time?
虽然我觉得里面要是 再有个凉亭会好一些
Well,I figure we still have the interior alcoves.
而且柱子的工作量也不小
Pilasters to do,which is no small task.
但是  我想按时完工没问题
But,yes. I think so.
我不得不说  我...
Listen,I have to say I
你为我所做的我真是感激不尽
I really appreciate all the effort that you put into this.
真希望有什么能补偿你 比如付你工钱 或是...
I wish there was some way I could,you know,pay you,or something.
有件事还真要请您帮忙
There is one thing you could do for me.
我的狱友
My cell mate.
啊 那个不用睡觉的疯子?
The inimitable Charles Patoshik.
海威尔?
Haywire?
原来你知道
Then you know.
你就忍忍吧
Hold it right there.
贝利克长官负全权责犯人的调度
Officer Bellick is in charge of cell transfers.
你得找他商量商量
You're gonna have to talk to him about that.
我试过  他好像认为我俩是天生的一对
I tried. But he seems to think we're a good match.
他威胁到你了没有?
Has he threatened you?
谁  海威尔还是贝利克?
Who? Haywire or Bellick?
不幸的是  除非能证明有暴力
Unfortunately,unless there's some evidence of violence.
或者性侵犯事件发生在你们之间
or sexual predation between cell mates.
其余的请求一般是不予受理的
those kinds of requests fall on deaf ears around here.
监狱里可没人有时间来管 什么性格不和之类的事情
Prison system's a little too crowded for requests based on personality.
这里可不是什么度假胜地
It's not exactly Sandals out there.
监狱长?
Warden?
不好意思  您妻子来了
Sorry. Your wife is here.
什么?
What?
不是应该4点到的么?
She's not supposed to be here till four o'clock.
贝蒂  无论如何也不能让她进来这里
Becky,do not let her come in here under any circumstances.
不能在结婚纪念日之前让她看到这个
She's not supposed to see this until our anniversary.
我这就出去
I'll be right out.
嗨  亲爱的
Hi,sweetheart.
来这么早
You're early.
咱们去吃点东西
Let's go eat.
你看起来怎么这么滑稽?
You're acting funny.
有么?
I am?
里面到底在干什么?
What's going on in there?
只是在看一些文件
Just going over some files.
贝蒂说你在开会
Becky said you were in a meeting.
不会又是托莱多事件吧?
This isn't Toledo all over again,is it?
托莱多?
Toledo?
怎么可能?
How can you say that?
那就不介意我进去看一下了
Then you won't mind if I look.
朱蒂
Uh,Judy...
监狱长  我没法再继续合作下去了
Warden,I'm not gonna be able to cooperate.
再这样下去  我会被杀死的
I'd get killed if I did.
约翰逊还在考虑
Johnson's still deciding.
好 没你事了
Then you and I are done.
你该早点告诉我
You should have just told me.
每当你接触犯人的时候  你知道我有多紧张
Well,you know how anxious I get when you come around the inmates.
贝蒂  叫警卫把约翰逊押回牢房
Becky,have a guard escort Johnson back to his cell.
我稍后再处理 走吧  咱们吃饭去
I'll deal with him later.Come on,let's eat.
你来这里干嘛?
What are you doing here?
我是你的律师
I'm your attorney.
代理你的案件
I'm representing you now.
如果你不介意的话
If that's all right with you.
上次我见到你时 还说我是个骗子
Last time I saw you,you called me a liar.
世事难料
Things have changed.
我现在相信你了
I believe you now.
我和克拉博·西蒙斯 的前女友莱提莎谈过了
I got in touch with Crab Simmons' ex-girlfriend,Leticia.
她证实了你的事情
She corroborated your story.
她会作证么?
Will she testify?
她失踪了
She's missing.
我也说不好  我认为她被特情局盯上了
I don't know.I think the Secret Service got to her.
特情局?
Secret Service?
他们也牵扯进来了
They've been poking around.
他们一出现  她就消失了 你怎么看?
They show up,she disappears.What do you think happenned?
我没想到能牵扯到高层
I didn't realise it was that high up,you know?
你知道我们面对的是什么人么?
Do you know what we're up against?
我只知道凭借咱们中的 任何一个人都应付不了的
I know it's a lot more than either of us can handle on our own.
司法公正处
Project Justice.
好像听说过?
Why have I heard of them?
命案都是他们处理
They handle death penalty cases.
那里有个叫本·福斯克的
There's a guy,Ben Forsik.
我把我所有掌握资料的拷贝都给他了
I sent him copies of everything I had.
你到那说明一下情况
You could tell him what you found.
或许他会帮助咱们
Maybe it'll be enough to bring him on board.
好的
OK.
塞巴斯蒂安怎么样了?
So,uh,how's Sebastian?
你指什么?
What do you mean?
你来这里找我  我是说 他不会介意吧?
Well,you being here.I mean,is he cool with it?
我没告诉他
I haven't talked to him.
婚约解除了
The engagement's off.
真对不起
Sorry.
你最好真是那么想的
You could at least say that like you mean it.
真的
I do.
你真是个差劲的说谎者
God,you always were a lousy liar.
是的
Yeah.
我还是去找司法公正处吧
I better get to Project Justice.
维罗妮卡?
Veronica?
多谢
Thank you.
我剩下的时间不多了
I didn't have a whole lot.
等你出来后再谢我也不迟
You can thank me when I get you out of here.
宝贝  是我  你在么?
Baby,it's me. Are you there?
喂? 你在么?
Hello? Are you there?
嘿  就算她在  她也显然不想理你
Hey. If she is,she obviously don't want to talk to you.
今天是星期三  宝贝儿
It's Wednesday,babe.
你会来看我的  对么?
You were gonna come around today,right?
好吧  我得挂了
Look,I gotta hang up now.
我得回去了
I gotta go back in the block.
你会来的  对么?
but...you're gonna be here today,right?
不要忘了我  亲爱的  我爱你
I'm your man,baby,and I love you.
永远爱你
I do.
像是某个地方
It's a pattern.
你说什么?
What did you say?
你的纹身...像是某个地方
Your tattoo. It's a pattern.
你看错了
You're seeing things.
让他和海威尔住在一起的是下策
Putting him in with Haywire is a low blow.
什么? 他已经没事了
What? The shrinks cleared Haywire for re-entry into Gen Pop.
而且他每天都会吃药  简直就像小猫一样乖
He's so doped up on meds he's like a kitten.
一只杀死亲生父母的小猫
A kitten who murdered both his parents.
出于尊敬  长官
With respect,sir.
您要是再给斯科菲尔德特权的话 会影响到您的信誉的
If you give Scofield preferential treatment,it'll undermine your credibility.
我知道您偏爱他  因为他很有头脑
I know you got a so spot for the guy because he's got brains.
并且能帮您弄那个玩意儿
And he's helping you with that contraption.
但他是个有暴力倾向的罪犯
But the guy's a violent criminal.
正如其他的犯人一样 受到惩罚是罪有应得
He deserves punishment as much as the rest of these guys.
你来这么久了也该知道
You've been here long you've to know that.
我是感化重于惩罚
I'm less interested in punishment than I am in rehabilitation.
把他和海威尔放在一起不是我的作风
And sticking him in with Haywire is not rehabilitation in my book.
老板 是您授权我负责调配犯人的
You delegated authority over Gen Pop to me,boss.
这我知道
I know I did.
那您就让我做自己的工作 或者让别人来做好了
You gotta let me do my job or pass it on somebody else.
布赖恩  别激动
Now,Brian,go easy.
我赋予你越来越多的责任是有原因的
There's a reason I'm giving you more and more responsibility.
我退休后  是要推荐你来坐我的位子的
When I retire,I'm recommending you to take my place.
别让我后悔
Don't make me regret it.
我想说的是  再考虑一下斯科菲尔德的情况
All I'm saying is,take another look at the Scofield situation.
我相信你的判断
I trust your judgment.
是的  长官
Yes,sir.
喂  喂  等一下  等一下
Hold up.
今天不是开放探亲日么 我们来这儿做什么?
This is supposed to be an open visitation. Why we doing it here?
去问你的访客
Ask your visitor.
你来这儿干嘛? 玛丽克鲁兹呢?
What are you doing here? Where's Maricruz?
她以后再也不会来了
She's not gonna be coming any more.
她病了?
Is she hurt?
不  没有  她很好  好极了  她只是...
No,no,she's fine,she's fine.She's just,uh...
她现在和我在一起了
She's with me now.
和你在一起?
She's with you now?
别逗了?
It's ajoke,right?
不  她已经决定了  伙计
No,she made a decision,man.
她选择了稳定的生活
She decided she needed stability.
她能从你那里得到么?
Is she gonna get that from you?
听着 你看 不管你怎么看我 但是...
You can think what you want about me but...
我至少没坐牢
I'm not the one who's in prison.
明白么
See?
至少在某方面我能为她做点什么
I actually can do something for her.
她让我先来这里和你谈谈 免得你失去理智
She wanted me to talk to you first in case you got mad...
你和我想的一样
You just proved my point.
你是个犯人  一辈子都是
You're a con.And that's all you'll ever be.
抓紧时间
Make it quick.
没错  他的确在这里
Yeah. He's right in here.
走开  乔奇
Take a walk,Choppy.
斯科菲尔德
Scofield.
这里是禁区
You're in a restricted area.
我正在院子里做狱工  我们需要些肥料
I'm doing yard work for PI.We need some fertiliser.
那你来工料区干什么?
Then why are you in the masonry section?
对了  你的脚怎么样了?
Oh,by the way,how's the foot?
不要再背着我去找监狱长了
Don't ever go around me to the Pope again.
滚吧
Now,move.
你知道么  海威尔?
You know what,Haywire?
我觉得咱们无法相处
I don't think we're gonna work out.
既然是我先来这里的 我觉得该走的是你
And since I was here first,I think you should go.
高中时有一次我拉屎在裤子上
I crapped myself once in junior high.
在上体育课的时候
During PE,
当时我们在打羽毛球
we were playing badminton,
我要从很多同学身边经过
and I knew I had to walk past a bunch of the other students
你知道  我要回更衣室
to get back to the locker room,
于是...
and so
我走了过去
I just started walking.
想找点乐子  做点别人从未做过的事情
And I tried to make fun of it,you know,before anyone else did.
我转过身...
So I turned around behind me,
然后说 "看那  我长尾巴了"
and I said,"Look,I have a tail."
我告诉了你我的秘密
I just shared a secret with you.
现在轮到你了
Now it's your turn.
想知道纹身画的是什么?
You want to know what the tattoos mean?
-没错  -什么也不是
-Yeah.  -Nothing.
嘿  嫩鸡
Hey,fish.
有什么进展么?
Making any progress?
你指和那个睡美人还是挖地道?
With Sleeping Beauty back there?Or with the digging?
都有
Either.
没进展
No.
但我知道该怎么做了
But I know what to do.
噢  真的么?
Oh,yeah?
只可惜  你没这个胆
Problem is,you don't got the stugots to do it.
阿布鲁奇  快走
Abruzzi,let's go.
回见
See ya.
真的么?
Yeah? Really?
替我向那个婊子养的问好
Well,tell the crazy son of a bitch I said hi.
时间到了
Wrap it up.
鲁思姑妈怎么样? 出院了没有?
How's Aunt Ruth? She out of hospital?
－时间到了  -等一下  妈妈
-Wrap it up.  -Hold on,Ma.
咬我嘛
Bite me.
看来你有麻烦了  伙计
OK. We got a problem now,man.
老子随便你
Let's handle it then.
没屁眼的杂种
That's what I thought.
喂?
Hello?
玛丽克鲁兹  是我  亲爱的 到底是怎么回事?
Maricruz? It's me.What's going on?
你和赫克托到底是怎么回事?
What's the deal with you and Hector?
你还打算瞒我多久?
When were you gonna tell me?
我瞒你什么了?
What?
丽塔·桑德拉去看过你了
That Rita Salda? A's been visiting you.
什么? 没错  赫克托告诉我的
What?  Yeah. Hector told me.
赫克托告诉你的 赫克托告诉你的
Hector told you.Hector told you.
他当然会这么说了 他是条毒蛇  是个骗子
Of course he told you.Baby,that guy is a snake. He's a liar.
他为什么要撒谎?
Why would he lie?
他为什么要骗你? 因为他想要占有你
Why would he lie?Because he's been trying to get into your pants
自从我们开始约会时他就那样了  这就是原因
since the minute we started dating.That's why.
你知道么?
You know what?
我不知道该去相信谁
I don't know what to believe.
我 亲爱的 相信我
Me,mami. Believe me.
是的  每周在电话旁等候两次
Yeah,while I wait by the phone twice a week.
亲爱的  你这是怎么了?
Baby,where is this coming from?
我也不知道
I don't know.
听着 最近发生了很多事
Look,there's just so many things.
昨天 我去找特里萨
Yesterday I went to Teresa's house,
看到她的宝宝
and I saw her baby.
就因为这个? 你等不及了么?
Is that what this is about?Your clock is ticking?
再过几年我就30岁了
Well,I am gonna be 30 in a few years.
亲爱的  你才25岁
You're 25.
你想要孩子? 咱们现在就可以
You want to get pregnant?Let's get pregnant right now.
亲爱的 你知道我不能在婚前怀孕的
I can't get pregnant until I'm married.
咱们会结婚的
We're gonna get married.
16个月后
In 16 months.
但是赫克托说  如果再出什么问题的话
Yeah,well,Hector says that if something goes wrong in there,
很可能会服全刑
you could serve your full sentence.
我可等不了10年
I can't wait ten years.
我不能再等10年啊  亲爱的
I can't wait ten years,baby.
再有16个月我就会出去了
I'm gonna be out in 16 months.
那要是再出什么差错呢?
But what if something does happen,huh?
亲爱的  我等不了那么久的
Baby,I can't wait that long.
我不能
I can't.
对不起  我得挂了
I'm sorry,I gotta go.
亲爱的...喂...
Hello? Baby,wait... Hello?
即使莱提莎·巴里斯肯出庭作证
Even if Leticia turned up,
她的证词也不会起太大的作用
her testimony would be worthless.
大多数有前科的瘾君子的证词是没人信的
By and large,most junkies with criminal records don't shine on the stand.
我只找到了这些证据
I just found all this out in the past couple days.
但我有信心能查出更多的
I'm confident I can find out more
我在这个案子上会全力以赴的
now that I'm devoting all my time to the case.
莱提莎在你办公室时特情局特工来过了
The agent who came to visit when Leticia was in your office,
他想要干嘛?
what did he want?
尼克  不要这样 你应该能理解的  多诺万女士
Nick,please. You've got to understand,
除非你能提供一些新的线索
unless there's new information for us,
布伦斯先生的案子我们已经审查过了
we've already reviewed Mr Burrows' case thoroughly.
你还能提供其他的证据么?
Do you have any new evidence?
不能  但是我...
No,but I...
但是...
But.
我想知道到底是有还是没有?
That is what you're telling us,right?
我需要确定一下
I need to clarify here.
是的 这正是我要说的
Yes. That is what I'm telling you.
但是福斯克先生 你不用一味的强调我没有证据
But,Mr Forsik,you don't need to point out what I don't have.
这点我很清楚
I'm well aware of that.
我来这是想寻求你的帮助的
I'm asking for your help.
我不想让一个无辜的人 为从未做过的事而承担死刑
I don't think a man should be killed for something he didn't do.
我相信这也是你们大厅里的那个宣言
That's what it says on your mission statement in the lobby.
我们有上万个诉讼请求需要受理
We get many requests for representation.
这点我知道
I'm sure you do...
我需要知道  哪些案件
And I have to decide which cases
是我们有能力做的
we're going to devote our limited resources to.
跑腿的活就让我来吧  福斯克先生
I will do all of the legwork,Mr Forsik,
但我在处理死刑犯的案件上没有经验
but with no experience in death penalty cases,
我只是恳请您能指点我一下
I'm just asking you to point me in the right direction.
求你了
Please.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们实在没有人手来管
We just don't have the manpower.
打扰您了
Thank you for your time.
她刚走
She's just leaving now.
这种交通下她到家至少还需半个小时
It'll take her a half-hour to get across town in this traffic.
用不了那么久
We're not gonna need nearly that much time.
我想我找到了
I've turned up quite a bit already.
嘿  你看到我的牙膏了么?
Hey. Hey,have you seen my toothpaste?
就放这儿了
It was right here.
没见过
I haven't seen it.
我总是放在同一个地方的
I always put it in the same place.
肯定能找到的
I'm sure it'll turn up.
那个纹身  是个迷宫
The tattoos - there's a maze.
离我远点
Get away from me.
我只是想看看...让我看一下 我简直为它着迷
I need to see 'em.You gotta show 'em to me.It's pulling me in.
我说了... 离我远点
I said,get away from me.
好的
OK.
他在身上纹了个迷宫图
He's got a maze on his skin.
是的  他在身上纹了个迷宫图
Man's got a maze on his skin.
为什么呢?
Why?
他为什么要这样做呢? 为什么?
Why would he do that? Why?
他为什么会把迷宫纹在身上呢?
Why would he put a maze on his skin?
我不知道
I don't know.
能找一下那个看守化学试剂的人吗?
How are your contacts in chemical lockup?
看是谁了
Depends who's asking.
我需要一瓶下水道除草剂  越快越好
I need a bottle of drain line root control,sooner than later.
号子里长草了?
You got weeds growing in your cell?
一瓶就够
Just one.
你找我?
Looking for me?
是的  我想就林肯·布伦斯 的案子问您几个问题
I wanted to ask some questions about the Lincoln Burrows case.
是么?
Yeah?
维罗妮卡·多诺万 林肯的辩护律师
I'm Veronica Donovan.I'm representing Lincoln on his appeal.
想问些什么?
What about it?
你是案发后
You were the first one
第一个到林肯家的人  对么?
to Lincoln's apartment the night of the murder.Right?
没错
Right.
我非常感激你能确切的 告诉我你都看到了什么
I'd really appreciate it if you could just tell me exactly what you saw.
有人举报称
Dispatch called.
看到布伦斯从 特伦斯·斯蒂德曼遇害的那间车库跑出来
Burrows was seen running from the garage where they found Steadman.
然后我们就去布伦斯家
So we went over to Burrows' place.
接着开始搜查
We spread out,
进入浴室
I took the bathroom.
然后看到您的代理人在洗血衣
I saw your client washing out the bloody pants.
警察 把手举起来
Police! Hands up.
我不用再告诉您那是斯蒂德曼的血了吧?
I don't need to tell you it was Steadman's blood.
按照当晚的报告
In the report you typed up,
你只说看到林肯站在浴室里  仅此而已
you said you saw Lincoln in the bathroom. That's all.
然后你又说看见他在洗血衣
Later,you testified that you saw him washing the pants.
到底哪个是真的?
Which one is it?
这重要么?
Does it matter?
你到底看没看见他在洗血衣?
Did you see him washing the pants or not?
是的
Yes.
他站起来  转过身
He stood up,turned around,
手还是湿的  一看就知道是他干的
his hands were all wet,looking guilty as hell.
是你的证词给他定罪的  你知道么?
Your testimony factored into his conviction.You know that,right?
夫人  如果你有任何疑问的话
You know,lady,if you got any other questions,
直接去找相关部门吧
just go through the department.
多诺万小姐
Ms Donovan?
我无意吓到你
I didn't mean to scare you.
你来这儿干什么?
What are you doing here?
司法公正局的 尼克·萨维恩
Nick Savrinn,with Project Justice.
我知道你是谁 你来这里干什么?
I know who you are,but what are you doing here?
我的上司可能认为林肯的案子不值一提
Look,my boss may not think Lincoln's case is worth looking into,
但我不这么想
but I do.
有个更快速的办法帮你解决烦恼
There's a quicker way to take care of your problem.
还有最聪明的办法
There's smarter ways,too.
大部分的有关死刑犯的案子
What stood out was that most death penalty cases
往往有10年左右的上诉期
take ten years to exhaust all appeals.
林肯却只有三年的时间
Lincoln got there in three.
一切显得那么顺理成章
So for it to be expedited,
定是出于某种政治的考虑  对么?
there had to have been some political influence,right?
特伦斯·斯蒂德曼是副总统的哥哥对么?
Steadman was the vice-president's brother.
这就不难相信了
It's not hard to believe.
怎么可能? 他们搞定了所有的法官?
How? They got to every judge that rejected his appeal?
根本用不着法官
It doesn't take ajudge.
只要她的手下稍微做些手脚就行了
All it takes is a little special attention from one of his clerks.
我对林肯被处死刑之快没有兴趣 我关心的是他们为什么要这么做
But how Lincoln got fast-tracked doesn't interest me. It's why.
若他真是被陷害的 究竟又是为了什么呢?
If he was set up,then why?
可能只有被害人才知道
I think the answer to that might lie in the victim.
我们知道什么? 他是菲尔德公司的首席执行官对么?
What do we know? He was a CEO of EcoField,right?
还是替代能源的倡导者
He was pushing alternative energy.
而且他做的很成功
Successfully pushing alternative energy.
于是石油公司  沙特人  甚至是我们的政府...
Oil companies,the Saudis,even our government ...
若斯蒂德曼消失的话 很多人都会从中受益
a lot of people stood to benefit with Steadman out of the picture.
你为什么现在才受理这案子?
Why did you wait till now to take up this case?
我也和别人一样  原以为是他干的
I thought he did it,like everybody else.
希望还为时不晚
I just hope it's not too late.
很可能已经晚了
It very well may be.
你要有心理准备
You need to prepare yourself for that.
那你呢?
What about you?
为什么选择干这行?
Why death penalty work?
我父亲含冤入狱15年
My father did 15 years for a crime he didn't commit.
我深知一旦你被政府盯上了
I know that when the government gets you in their cross hairs,
就很难再翻身了
you stand very little chance.
这就是为什么
That's why.
那么现在...需要我帮忙么?
Now,do you want my help?
-我想加入  -太晚了
-I want in. -Too late.
让我做什么都行  看见这双手了么?
I'll do anything.See this hand?
简直就是挖掘机
These hands are digging machines.
你想去中国? 我就挖到中国
And if you want to go to China ,I'll get you to China.
我会像疯狂的穿山甲一样为你打地洞
I'll dig like a psychotic rodent if I have to.
嫩鸡... 你一定要带上我
Fish,I gotta be back in.
就目前来看  你没法回来
As of right now,there is no in.
那边的凡高兄弟  是我的新狱友
Van Gogh over there is my new cell mate.
你总会有办法的  对么?
But you're gonna do something about it ,right?
-你会把他弄走的  -如果必要的话 我会的
-You're gonna get rid of him. -I'll do what's necessary.
爱死你了
You're my boy.
那你打算怎么办?
So how you gonna do it?
只好这样了
Let's just put it this way.
有人得受些皮肉之苦了
Someone's gonna get hurt.
我们怎么没注意到这个?
How did we miss this guy?
斯科菲尔德的父亲 在他出生时就已经不在了
Scofield's father was out of the picture by the time he was born.
于是就跟了母亲的姓
Took his mother's name.
斯科菲尔德没有前科 而且还是个全职的工程师
All right. Scofield had no priors and a full-time job as an engineer?
没错
Correct.
有一天他突然去抢银行  然后弃械投降
Then he goes and robs a bank,discharging a gun in the process,
宣判的时候  他海申请被关在狐狸河监狱
so in sentencing he could manoeuvre his way to Fox River,
同时他哥哥在那里的日子却不到一个月了
where his brother's scheduled to die in less than a month.
显然他是有预谋的
Obviously,something's up.
不过兄弟同在一所 监狱服刑倒也不稀奇
With all due respect,brothers are incarcerated together all over in the country.
或许只是巧合
It may just be a coincidence.
把弟弟弄走
Move on the younger brother.
做干净点 以免坏了咱们的大事
Do it pre-emptively,before anything rises up,bites any of us in the ass.
是路径图...
It's a pathway.
它到底通向哪儿?
Where does it lead?
你要把我带哪儿去?
Where are you taking me?
你疯了么?
What? Are you nuts?
长官
Officer!
我要见长官
I need an officer!
出什么事了?
What the hell's the problem down here?
噢...这个婊子养的
What the... Son of a bitch.
打开40号
Open up on 40.
他身上有张路径图  通向某处
He's got the pathway on his body.It leads somewhere.
退后  海威尔
Back off,Haywire
不  看他的纹身  是张路径图
No,look.Look at his tattoos. It's a pathway.
海威尔  我说了"退后" 你要来点胡椒水么?
Haywire.I said back off.You want a hot shot?
我都说了  你看他的...
I'm telling you, look... Argh!
退后  伙计 快进来帮忙
Back off, man.
把他带走
Let's go. Get him out of here.
那是通向地狱(之路)
It leads to hell!
通向地狱
通向地狱之路
It's a pathway to hell!
他要把我们带到地狱
He's taking us all to hell!
老伙计又团聚了 真是不错啊
So, the gang's all back together again.Well, ain't that swell?
告诉过你不要背着我去找监狱长
I told you not to go around me with the Pope.
可你就是不听  是不是?
But you just keep making waves, don't you?
回来真好  欢迎归来
Good to be back, man. Good to have you back.
咱们什么时候开始?
So, when do we get started?
下午好 斯科菲尔德先生
Good afternoon, Mr Scofield.
你好
Hello.
今天感觉如何?
How are you feeling today?
很好
Real good.
又怎么了?
What happened?
打篮球时吃了一暗肘
Caught an elbow playing basketball.
我能看一下么?
Mind if I take a look?
当然
By all means.
你会把命丢了的  知道么?
You know you're gonna get killed in here, right?
要是再不小心点的话
If you're not careful.
我答应你
I'll make you a bet.
要能活着出去
When I get out of here, alive,
就请你共进晚餐
I'll take you to dinner.
午餐或者咖啡什么的
Lunch. Cup of coffee.
迈克尔  这种表达魅力的方式
Michael, this charm act
正是你惹祸上身的原因
could be exactly what's getting you into trouble out in the yard.
往前点
Lean forward.
好的...
All right.
你来到停车场
You went to the parking garage,
特伦斯·斯蒂德曼就已经死了
Terence Steadman is already dead.
没错
That's right.
你发现后就跑掉了... 带着枪
You saw that, you ran? Took the gun?
把枪扔了  扔哪儿了?
Dumped the gun. Where?
下水道  位于范布伦和威尔士
Storm drain. Van Buren and Wells.
至今未被发现
Nobody ever found it.
好的  那之后你做了什么?
What did you do after that?
回到家?
Go back to your apartment?
是的
Yeah.
我吓坏了  想弄明白是怎么回事
I was freaking out,trying to figure out what had happened.
然后发现浴缸里有条血迹斑斑的裤子
Then I saw the bloody pants in the tub.
一分钟之后警察就赶到了
The cops, they busted in a minute after I got there.
裤子上有斯蒂德曼的血迹
The pants, with Steadman's blood on them.
第一个到现场的警察说亲眼 看到你在浴缸里洗那条裤子
First cop on the scene says he saw you washing them in the tub.
他在说谎
He's lying.
我手湿是因为洗脸弄的
My hands were wet after splashing water on my face.
警察 把手举起来 把手举起来
Police! Let's see the hands! Hands up!
我从未碰过那条裤子
I never touched those pants.
再说说枪的事
Which brings us back to the gun,
被你扔掉的那把枪
the one you dumped.
这是设计好了的
It was planted.
只能这么解释
Only way it could have got there.
弹道完全吻合
Ballistics matched it to a slug...
枪是嫁祸的 他们设计好了的
The gun was planted.
就像血裤一样
Just like the pants.
枪上有你的指纹
Your fingerprints were all over the gun.
博...
Bo.
博是谁?
Who's Bo?
这一切都是他安排的
He's the guy who arranged everything.
他让我前一天的晚上去找他
He had me come round the night before,
试了几把枪  看哪把最适合
try a few guns, see which one felt right.
那时就设计好了
That was the setup.
凶器肯定就在那些枪之中
One of those must have been the murder weapon.
枪上也就有了我的指纹
That's how they got my fingerprints on the gun.
一定是这样
Had to be.
那么这个叫 博的人...
All right. So this Bo,
他逼你做这个  来偿还那9万元的欠款
he coerces you into doing this, all to clear a $90,000 debt?
还扬言要杀了我儿子
He was gonna kill my son.
进展如何?
Well?
一大堆"不是我干的" 这些又起不了作用
Lot of "I didn't do it", don't count for much.
监控录像  记录林肯扣动扳机的那盘...
The tape that shows Lincoln pulling the trigger.
还在你手里么?  是的
You got it?  Yeah.
如果林肯说的属实  那盘录像就是伪造的
If Lincoln's telling the truth, the tape's lying
咱们应该好好看看 看能不能发现什么
I think we should have a look,decide for ourselves.
没人
You're clear.
既然化学试剂能够腐蚀钢管
If the chemicals can eat through the iron pipes,
为什么牙膏筒却没事?
how come they can't eat through the tube?
只有当两种试剂混合才会发生发应
When the chemicals are combined,they become a corrosive.
你是学化学的?
You studied chemistry or something?
不是在学校学的
Not in school.
你在医务室做什么了
But what you're doing up there in the infirmary,
又和这里的事情有什么联系呢?
what's it gotta do with this here?
打通这堵墙只是个开始
Getting through this wall is just the beginning.
这里和外墙之间还有很多房间
There's a whole lot of real estate in between here and the outside walls.
医务室是最靠近外墙的建筑
The infirmary's the closest building to those walls.
...也是安全措施中最薄弱的环节
And the weakest link in the security chain.
酷
Cool.
我想挖的已经差不多了
I think I've removed enough grout to bust through.
现在帮我弄点噪声
I'm gonna need you to make some noise.
就这么点本事么?
Is that the best you can do?
要相信我  哥们
Have some faith,papi.
要相信我
Have some faith.
闭嘴
Shut up!
都给我闭嘴
Not one more word.
谁再出声就关禁闭
Next inmate that opens his mouth goes in the hole.
没事了
We're good.
你还好吧?
You OK?
工作的事
Work.
没什么
It's fine.
我来
I got it.
还算顺利吧?
Everything all right?
非常的顺利
Couldn't be better.
进来坐会么? 我们正要吃晚餐呢
You want to come in?We just sat down to eat.
不  我只想私下和你聊聊
No. I just wanted to stop by to tell you in person.
问题解决了
Problem solved.
这是什么?
What's this?
移送申请
That is a transfer request.
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德 明天就会被转走了
Michael Scofield is getting shipped out tomorrow.
晚安
Have a good night.